<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Karan Luthra</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/feeds/c.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.karanluthra.in/</id><updated>2014-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Half Time: What's up at Trojitá</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2014/07/half-time-whats-up-at-trojita/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2014-07-01:2014/07/half-time-whats-up-at-trojita/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Second half has just begun for the GSoC coding period as well as for the year 2014. We are all more warmed up and pacing up to see another "you will be glued to the second half", but let's take a look at what has kept me involved in Trojitá uptil now. My &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2014/luthrak/5685265389584384"&gt;project proposal&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="http://trojita.flaska.net/"&gt;Trojitá&lt;/a&gt; is to:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite Trojitá's SMTP code to enable it to use Trojitá's Sockets, and make it a first class citizen wrt the code quality, robustness, maintainabilty and features.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring essential features and UI changes that will make Trojitá more usable and ready for a larger user-base.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the second goal consists of small tasks that would also help a newbie (me) get more comfortable with the code, me and my mentors decided to start with these small tasks first. This is what has been done uptil now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network Reconnection Attempts&lt;br /&gt;
Trojitá got a feature to automatically start a reconnect attempt cycle whenever there's a network error.&lt;br /&gt;
Previously, whenever the application was hit by a network error, it would switch to offline mode and inform the user by throwing an error message (which would be a modal message box). Now, a message box is still thrown the first time an error is faced and attempts for reconnect begin. To keep in line with Trojitá's prinicples of being less resource hungry and be usable for users with expensive mobile connections, any two reconnect attempts are separated with timeout that doubles every step. So, timeouts go like 5 secs, 10 secs,.. 160 secs, 300 secs (Inspired by the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exponential_backoff"&gt;Exponential Backoff&lt;/a&gt; algorithm I came across in Computer Networks class). And beyond that, attempts are made every 5 mins or manually stopped and restarted by the user. An unattended message box gets closed if network reconnects successfully. &lt;em&gt;Status: Merged in master&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forwarding Support&lt;br /&gt;
Trojitá already had the ability to treat whole messages dragged and dropped into the attachments view in a composer as messages to be forwarded as dot.eml files. In addition to that, trojitá now has a patch (under review atm) that would enable forward as attachment by a single click from the GUI. This includes mangling the subject of the original message and prefixing the "Fwd: " string, as well as marking the original message as $Forwarded. &lt;em&gt;Status: Under &lt;a href="https://git.reviewboard.kde.org/r/118606/"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improvements around Compose Widget  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One improvement is a bug fix that allows any changes to the subject field or the recipients fields to be treated as modifications eligible for storing in a draft. &lt;em&gt;Status: Merged in master&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another improvement is the ability to switch the reply mode { private reply, reply to all, reply to all but me, mailing list reply} from the composer as well (previously, a mode would be picked up at the time of creating the compose reply dialog and switching between modes wasn't possible unless a new dialog be opened). The change of mode triggers the automatic setting up of recipients in the current composer and modifying the recipients puts the reply mode in a fifth state, named "hand picked recipients". This patch is under &lt;a href="https://git.reviewboard.kde.org/r/118802/"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; and it is yet to be finalised &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in the compose window should this dropdown menu be placed.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another improvement (that won't be visible to the user) is a change in how a GUI::ComposeWidget is created. A compose widget needs a parent (MainWindow), an MSA(Mail Submissin Agent) object, a settings (QSettings) object and a couple of purpose specific parameters that can pre-fill the fields in the composer (eg: subject, body(quoted), in-reply-to, etc in the case of a "reply"). Due to increasing use-cases for the Compose Widget (Message Forwarding and Message Redirectin are two such that are being added in this GSoC project), we felt the need to refactor the ComposeWidget and provide a static API for creating ComposeWidget instances with specific roles. It looks like this:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/karanluthra/37c3f65e229761002958.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/karanluthra/37c3f65e229761002958#file-static-cw"&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half has started off with shifting the focus onto the bigger task of rewriting the SMTP library. While writing this blog post I realised how it has become a long one to read, and I will try and write about whats up with SMTP more regularly, and hopefully as smaller posts. I find twitter to be a better output stream while in the code-sprint mood and you can follow me on Twitter, I am &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/karanluthra06"&gt;@karanluthra06&lt;/a&gt;. Best wishes to all GSoCers; Let's make this second half the most exciting ever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers! :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="c++"></category><category term="gsoc"></category><category term="trojita"></category><category term="kde"></category><category term="foss"></category></entry><entry><title>This summer I'm flipping bits, not burgers</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2014/06/flipping-bits-not-burgers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2014-06-10:2014/06/flipping-bits-not-burgers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wasn't even checking the results that night when I got a congratulatory email from a friend. There was nothing else one could be congratulated for on that night, except for GSoC results. As difficult as it was to believe I found it to be true that my proposal indeed got selected for the 10th &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/homepage/google/gsoc2014"&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;, for the summers of 2014. I will be working under &lt;a href="http://www.kde.org/"&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; and my &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2014/luthrak/5685265389584384"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; aims to improve how &lt;a href="http://trojita.flaska.net"&gt;Trojitá&lt;/a&gt; sends email over SMTP and make it as robust and capable as the IMAP part, the USP of the email client. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first contribution to Free and Open Source Software began with a &lt;a href="http://quickgit.kde.org/?p=trojita.git&amp;amp;a=commit&amp;amp;h=6f14132d37666148e2db44be9e051816bb33daca"&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; for Trojitá in February. It was a feature request that I thought I could work on, and while it took me very long to bring the patch to the quality that could get it merged, it was a different high I experienced when I heard "Ship It!" for the first time in my life, and saw my name in the 'About Trojitá' menu of the email client I had started loving to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="About Trojitá - List of Contributors" src="/images/trojita_authors.png" title="About Trojitá - List of Contributors" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reward of working with open source projects. You can imagine the impact your code can have on thousands (and millions? :D) of users and this motivates you to improve the patch each time it gets returned from a review by mentors. Another encouragement is that open source projects do not care about your exam scores, your university's reputation, or even your majors for that matter! I was thinking hard how to spend the summers after my final semester and before joining the job I have been offered through campus placement, and Google Summer of Code seemed like the dream option to me. However, I was never too sure about getting selected as I am not an experienced developer, so I kept exploring other options while planning to keep contributing to Trojitá at my own, slow pace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did on the morning after the results night, was clear all the bookmarked interships! I have cleared most of the distractions by now, and got another &lt;a href="http://quickgit.kde.org/?p=trojita.git&amp;amp;a=commit&amp;amp;h=7708aaa7fda2877a868a542e9a1335683c9cbdb7"&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; submitted recently. I am still lagging behind schedule, but it's only going to get better from now :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are even one bit curious about how Open Source projects, GSoC, or Computer Science outside your exam-syllabus works, then keep watching this space. I will try and blog as much as I can about all that I am upto :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to the Summer of 2014! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GSoC goodies" src="/images/gsoc-diary.jpg" title="GSoC goodies, to begin with :D" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="c++"></category><category term="gsoc"></category><category term="trojita"></category><category term="kde"></category><category term="foss"></category></entry></feed>