<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Karan Luthra</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/feeds/inspirational.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.karanluthra.in/</id><updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Is it time?</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2012/10/is-it-time/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2012-10-03:2012/10/is-it-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is it time, for me to close my eyes?
To use the switch, to turn it off?
Seems like the closing of the eyes,
would only trigger a tear to fall
Seems like, taking a breather,
would only make me regret the call&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it time, to step aside?
To take the seat, and watch the game?
Seems like its a runway on tight schedule,
Take off, right now! Or else, dont blame.
Remind me of the player I wanted to be,
then anyone less, I wouldnt want to see!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="inspirational"></category></entry><entry><title>Gandhi, come to my college!</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2012/10/gandhi-come-to-my-college/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2012-10-02:2012/10/gandhi-come-to-my-college/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Be the change you wish to see in the world", keh gaye hamare Dearest Gandhi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuck it, who wants to read about what Gandhi said when he was alive? His 
picture on the Indian Currency says a lot everyday, every minute, for everyone! 
But these questions really bother me :
Why does today's leader very much wants Gandhi only in his pocket, and not even 
intend to incorporate, or even respectfully understand his ideals?
Why does it take so much to be pro-active?
Why do we let ourselves be anything less than perfect, at what we do?
Why don't we tackle the feeling of being incompetent every morning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this agitation started in the morning, when I started contemplating over how 
a particular technical festival in my college is being organized. I am an 
engineering student, and I have put my heart and soul since the past three weeks 
into getting sponsors for the events under my department. To clarify, my 
father's job designation or my mother's social status doesn't help me get money 
from investors. And I am proud of this part, that I pursue such jobs solely 
because I love adding some value to the organizations I am associated with. And 
I know that there are so many, so many people in the college who feel the same. 
But then, whats wrong? Why do we, as a group, always miss perfectionism by, say 
like the last few points? All this inspite of having many, many good leaders, in 
a crowd of others who are not true to even themselves!
I am lucky enough to sit at home on this national holiday, and ponder over these 
things. Most of us are probably holidaying in some shimla or mussourie, sitting 
fat over the bundles of Gandhi Currency notes we have been successful in 
accumulating.
And I am even luckier to have started off with Gandhi, I just came across a G+ 
update which quotes Gandhi ji saying “Anger and intolerance are the twin enemies 
of correct understanding”. And I totally believe that we need to BE THE CHANGE, 
so Ill start afresh, keeping aside all the anger and intolerance towards the 
TechFest situation :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let this be the thought for the day :
“ There are seven things that will destroy us :
Wealth without work, pleasure without conscience, knowledge without character, 
religion without sacrifice, politics without principle, science without 
humanity, and Business without Ethics”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen! :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="college"></category><category term="inspirational"></category></entry></feed>