<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Karan Luthra</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/feeds/internship.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.karanluthra.in/</id><updated>2013-06-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Six Weeks to Undo Sixth Semester's Sins</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2013/06/six-weeks-to-undo-sixth-semesters-sins/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2013-06-17:2013/06/six-weeks-to-undo-sixth-semesters-sins/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introductory paragraphs are supposed to be short, else the reader gets put off, 
they say! Mine was running long enough, so I made it the second one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently been called 'mugga' by my younger sibling! I have been called 
that every alternate day, for the last two weeks! I know I dint mug anything, 
just accepted my inability at producing what semester exams at my university 
expect from students (yes, took me a lot of time to figure this out), and then 
just tried to remain sincere with my plan. But that sincerity would zero down to 
frustration after most exams, when it seemed pointless to have gotten through 
all those books and notes, for the test was only about your ability to link the 
keywords in the question to the keywords you remember from the last 24 hours' 
preparation. Write a few points that could be 'highlighted' to qualify your 
answer correct. Now, to quantify your effort, fill sheets with what-so-ever crap 
you can think of. Yes, writing the question again is also acceptable!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now after all the junk, its time to feed some spinach to our minds! I have quite 
a list. So would all my peers. But, I'm gonna share it here. I have heard 
talking about it helps people stick to their plans, so lets try it this time! 
Here's a list of all that I hope to read, learn and do in the next six-eight 
weeks before college reopens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the most of my Summer Training: I admire my classmates who are coding for 
GSOC, or working at startups, or going to IITs or other research internships. 
Myself, I just wanna make the most out of what I got in hand, and I consider 
myself lucky for that. With my cousins help, I got an opportunity at 
TechMahindra, and I am really looking forward to having good exposure and a 
hard-working time there, irrespective of the project I will be assigned 
(tomorrow)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books to read: I will be travelling 2-4 hours everyday, and NOT driving, so 
i started off with Stephen Hawking's The Grand Design. Next up will be Steve 
Jobs biography by Karen Blumenthal. Lets finish these two, and I would have 
decided the next book by then :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs to follow: I recently discovered two of my college seniors, (they 
don't know me) have quite a few good posts. Otherwise too, they both really 
command respect for their intellect, and I've subscribed to their blogs 
krspeak.wordpress.com and anupamguha.wordpress.com. There are a lot more seniors 
who inspire me, but that can become a future blog post!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I already follow zenhabits.net and recently found zenpencils.com. There 
isn't much common other than the word ZEN and the motive to help readers. And 
this isn't a coincidence, but I really wanna figure out what ZEN really is, too. 
I will find other sources for that though. And articles about Taoism. One good 
option is to follow relevant groups and people on G+. (A blog post on G+ and its 
perks soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical articles/blogs: First, my brother had been telling me about ESR's 
philosophy during our chats in my study breaks, and I am starting with The Art 
of Unix Programming right away! Second, I had subscribed to Smashing Magazine 
don't know how long back, but never read it seriously! Whenever I can squeeze 
out time, I'll check it out in detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To write/learn/code/research: I really find it interesting to observe how 
the masses perceive facebook. The most interesting part: most of us need to be 
much more aware and alert about what's good and what's not, about FB. After 
making the changes to my own profile, I'll write about what are the simplest few 
changes we can make to our FB usage. And my list of alternatives to facebook, 
for spending time online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, I am going to experiment a lot with the ideas I had during exams. Some 
of them are small enough to be a reason to learn web development, and a few 
might be big enough to be considered for my university project. But, lots of 
work needed here first of all!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew! I myself just figured out for the first time how much I had kept for 
post-exams, after compiling this list!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing everything may seem unrealistic, but of course, I'll approach all these in 
little steps. I have been adding links, so that if someone finds any of them 
interesting, I have a partner to chat about something cool and of course, doing 
things together helps us achieve a lot more :) &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="internship"></category><category term="productivity"></category><category term="college"></category></entry></feed>