<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Karan Luthra</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/feeds/marathon.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.karanluthra.in/</id><updated>2013-12-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Couch to The Great Delhi Run</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2013/12/couch-to-great-delhi-run/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2013-12-14:2013/12/couch-to-great-delhi-run/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm a Computer Science and Engineering student, and if you know ten of them, not 
more than three would you call fit and active. Above that, I am Punjabi, a beer 
lover, and I have spent most of my PT periods in school in the Music Room. In 
fact, the only thing constantly growing in my life since the last four-five 
years was my belly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, WAS. I will be running The Great Delhi Run tomorrow, which is a part of the 
Airtel Delhi Half Marathon, an Annual event for Delhites. I will be running 
about 6 kilometers, and this time I am not just hoping, I am sure that I will be 
able to complete the length of the race. Thanks to the spirit of this event, I 
am feeling better than my preparation. Also, over the last 2 months, I have very 
much learnt to believe in the Me vs Me ideology. Add to that the wonderful crowd 
of active and lively people, with whom I will match my steps tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start from JLN Stadium at 9.30 in the morning, while the 22 km event 
would have begun earlier. We will be running around the Lodhi Road area and this 
is gonna be a new experience for me as I have only been to jogging tracks of 
local parks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this aside, the thing that is making me really excited is the people I will 
meet, the new friends I will make. Quoting the speaker from runningandliving.com 
at the Get Active Expo last week, "Above all, have fun, have a good time". They 
also provided amazing guidance, and a checklist for participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's gonna be a challenge tomorrow, and I am sure I will get past it and come 
and write another blog post (this time with pictures)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, 9:30 AM, 6 kms. Cheer for me :D&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="fitness"></category><category term="running"></category><category term="delhi"></category><category term="marathon"></category></entry></feed>