<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Karan Luthra</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.karanluthra.in/</id><updated>2014-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>BollyYoYo v/s Music</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2014/01/bollyyoyo-vs-music/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2014-01-04:2014/01/bollyyoyo-vs-music/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On a bad day, I felt something was wrong with me when I couldn't contribute much to the 'hot' discussion about the latest songs, the one with the 'tooh', and the 'blue eyes'. "I haven't heard these songs" got me a stare, the eyes filled with shock and ridicule. A more generous person in the group asked me what music do I listen to instead. I couldn't answer that properly (I believe many of us are unable to), and probably also because I was sure the answer wont excite anyone there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is a good day, and I'd like to take a re-attempt at that question. I have been listening (and watching) MTV Unplugged Season 3 sessions on repeat since morning. Listen to the same song a 50 times, and you still find a piece that you missed noticing the last time. Also include MTV Coke Studio sessions from India as well as Pakistan. These shows have produced some of the most attention-consuming soundtracks in the last few years. Attention consuming like (an analogy) Sherlock, compared to other shows like BBT or F.R.I.E.N.D.S. Like Inception (and many others) amongst hollywood movies. Like what Madras Cafe was to Indian cinema and 24 to Indian Television, recently. These shows have the feeling of live music: they are recorded in one take, with real musicians, and give artists ample opportunity to showcase their creativity. This freedom to the artist is what makes "Music" out of "Songs". Sprinkle the collaboration word over, and it turns into Chicken Soup for the Music Soul! Everyone brings their palette of colours to the stage, from the backup vocalists to the solo instrumentalists to the main artists. Awesomeness lies in this experimentation, in this coming together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is experimentation behind bollywood music too, when they experiment with the hairstyle of the actor, the size of the actress's dress, or that eureka moment when they find the "munni" "sheila" or "tooh" of the next song! Congratulations :)
Every song will find listeners. But not every listener will find Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might not be able to answer "What music do you listen to, then?" when asked again. But I can sure share my list of favorites from these shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-S5U2GXKBSo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saari Raat, Noori&lt;/em&gt;, Coke Studio Pakistan, Season 2&lt;/a&gt;. After listening to Noori live at Seher, this song has been the most played on my player, and in my head. Each and every moment in this song is awesome!  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v11rpZgzOCk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hallelujah, Karsh Kale ft Shilpa Rao&lt;/em&gt;, Coke Studio @ MTV Season 2&lt;/a&gt;. Amazing composition by Warren Mendonsa, Karsh Kale's rendition of the Leonard Cohen classic, and Shilpa's voice.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L-9s4nTLSdA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madari (Jamura), Vishal Dadlani&lt;/em&gt; Mtv Coke Studio Season 2&lt;/a&gt;. Vishal Dadlani and Sonu Kakkar. It is an amazing feeling to hear Vishal Dadlani singing songs like these, after having heard him with Pentagram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uMF8npZN5wE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Khamaj, Shafqat Amanat Ali Khan&lt;/em&gt;, Coke Studio Pakistan, Season 2&lt;/a&gt;. The freedom of the artist I was talking about above. The "thairaav" in his voice can be witnessed here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IvU-RyEPlkQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phir Le Aaya, Arijit Singh&lt;/em&gt;, Mtv Unplugged Season 3&lt;/a&gt;. This song! It deserved a format like Mtv Unplugged. And Arijit deserved this song too!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Is it time?</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2012/10/is-it-time/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2012-10-03:2012/10/is-it-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is it time, for me to close my eyes?
To use the switch, to turn it off?
Seems like the closing of the eyes,
would only trigger a tear to fall
Seems like, taking a breather,
would only make me regret the call&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it time, to step aside?
To take the seat, and watch the game?
Seems like its a runway on tight schedule,
Take off, right now! Or else, dont blame.
Remind me of the player I wanted to be,
then anyone less, I wouldnt want to see!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="inspirational"></category></entry><entry><title>Gandhi, come to my college!</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2012/10/gandhi-come-to-my-college/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2012-10-02:2012/10/gandhi-come-to-my-college/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Be the change you wish to see in the world", keh gaye hamare Dearest Gandhi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuck it, who wants to read about what Gandhi said when he was alive? His 
picture on the Indian Currency says a lot everyday, every minute, for everyone! 
But these questions really bother me :
Why does today's leader very much wants Gandhi only in his pocket, and not even 
intend to incorporate, or even respectfully understand his ideals?
Why does it take so much to be pro-active?
Why do we let ourselves be anything less than perfect, at what we do?
Why don't we tackle the feeling of being incompetent every morning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this agitation started in the morning, when I started contemplating over how 
a particular technical festival in my college is being organized. I am an 
engineering student, and I have put my heart and soul since the past three weeks 
into getting sponsors for the events under my department. To clarify, my 
father's job designation or my mother's social status doesn't help me get money 
from investors. And I am proud of this part, that I pursue such jobs solely 
because I love adding some value to the organizations I am associated with. And 
I know that there are so many, so many people in the college who feel the same. 
But then, whats wrong? Why do we, as a group, always miss perfectionism by, say 
like the last few points? All this inspite of having many, many good leaders, in 
a crowd of others who are not true to even themselves!
I am lucky enough to sit at home on this national holiday, and ponder over these 
things. Most of us are probably holidaying in some shimla or mussourie, sitting 
fat over the bundles of Gandhi Currency notes we have been successful in 
accumulating.
And I am even luckier to have started off with Gandhi, I just came across a G+ 
update which quotes Gandhi ji saying “Anger and intolerance are the twin enemies 
of correct understanding”. And I totally believe that we need to BE THE CHANGE, 
so Ill start afresh, keeping aside all the anger and intolerance towards the 
TechFest situation :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let this be the thought for the day :
“ There are seven things that will destroy us :
Wealth without work, pleasure without conscience, knowledge without character, 
religion without sacrifice, politics without principle, science without 
humanity, and Business without Ethics”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amen! :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="college"></category><category term="inspirational"></category></entry></feed>