<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Karan Luthra</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/feeds/trojita.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.karanluthra.in/</id><updated>2014-05-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>This summer I'm flipping bits, not burgers</title><link href="http://blog.karanluthra.in/2014/05/flipping-bits-not-burgers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Karan Luthra</name></author><id>tag:blog.karanluthra.in,2014-05-31:2014/05/flipping-bits-not-burgers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wasn't even checking the results that night when I got a congratulatory email from a friend. There was nothing else one could be congratulated for on that night, except for GSoC results. As difficult as it was to believe I found it to be true that my proposal indeed got selected for the 10th &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/homepage/google/gsoc2014"&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;, for the summers of 2014. I will be working under &lt;a href="http://www.kde.org/"&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; and my &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/project/details/google/gsoc2014/luthrak/5685265389584384"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; aims to improve how &lt;a href="http://trojita.flaska.net"&gt;Trojitá&lt;/a&gt; sends email over SMTP and make it as robust and capable as the IMAP part, the USP of the email client. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first contribution to Free and Open Source Software began with a &lt;a href="http://quickgit.kde.org/?p=trojita.git&amp;amp;a=commit&amp;amp;h=6f14132d37666148e2db44be9e051816bb33daca"&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; for Trojitá in February. It was a feature request that I thought I could work on, and while it took me very long to bring the patch to the quality that could get it merged, it was a different high I experienced when I heard "Ship It!" for the first time in my life, and saw my name in the 'About Trojitá' menu of the email client I had started loving to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="About Trojitá - List of Contributors" src="/images/trojita_authors.png" title="About Trojitá - List of Contributors" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reward of working with open source projects. You can imagine the impact your code can have on thousands (and millions? :D) of users and this motivates you to improve the patch each time it gets returned from a review by mentors. Another encouragement is that open source projects do not care about your exam scores, your university's reputation, or even your majors for that matter! I was thinking hard how to spend the summers after my final semester and before joining the job I have been offered through campus placement, and Google Summer of Code seemed like the dream option to me. However, I was never too sure about getting selected as I am not an experienced developer, so I kept exploring other options while planning to keep contributing to Trojitá at my own, slow pace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did on the morning after the results night, was clear all the bookmarked interships! I have cleared most of the distractions by now, and got another &lt;a href="http://quickgit.kde.org/?p=trojita.git&amp;amp;a=commit&amp;amp;h=7708aaa7fda2877a868a542e9a1335683c9cbdb7"&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; submitted recently. I am still lagging behind schedule, but it's only going to get better from now :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are even one bit curious about how Open Source projects, GSoC, or Computer Science outside your exam-syllabus works, then keep watching this space. I will try and blog as much as I can about all that I am upto :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers to the Summer of 2014! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GSoC goodies" src="/images/gsoc-diary.jpg" title="GSoC goodies, to begin with :D" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="c++"></category><category term="gsoc"></category><category term="trojita"></category><category term="kde"></category><category term="foss"></category></entry></feed>